<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<databaseChangeLog
  xmlns="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog/1.9"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog/1.9
         http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog/dbchangelog-1.9.xsd">

<changeSet author="default" id="admin_user">
 <insert tableName="person">
 <column name="username">admin</column>
 <column name="guid">admin</column>
 <column name="domain">public</column>
 <column name="email">none@email.com</column>
 <column name="organization">/MAIN/</column>
 <column name="password">c86d41b402412f9af156e9e62e20bcd0</column>
 <column name="access_level">10</column>
 <column name="industry">Academia</column>
 </insert>
</changeSet>    

<changeSet author="default" id="site_content_1">
 <insert tableName="site_content">
   <column name="label">index.main</column>
   <column name="page">index.html</column>
   <column name="content"><![CDATA[ 
 <h2>With the siSPOTR tools you can:</h2>
    <ol>
      <li>Identify candidate siRNA/shRNA sequences for your gene of interest with a low potential for off-targeting.</li>
      <li>Evaluate the off-targeting potential for any RNAi sequence.</li>
      <li>View a list of all predicted off-targets for siRNA candidates, along with information on the site-type composition and probability of being off-targeted.</li>
      <li>BLAST your sequence to search for siRNA-like on/off-targeting</li>
    </ol>
    <br/>
]]></column>
 </insert>
</changeSet>    




<changeSet author="default" id="site_content_2">
 <insert tableName="site_content">
   <column name="label">help.faq</column>
   <column name="page">help.html</column>
   <column name="content"><![CDATA[
 href="#">What is considered a good POTS value?</a></h3>
    <div>
      <p>
   For
    sequences designed for use in human cells, &le; 30 is ideal.
    Regardless of POTS, use proper controls to ensure effects are
    specific to your intended target knockdown.
          </p>
    </div>

    <h3><a href="#">What format should my sequences be in?</a></h3>
    <div>
      <p>
    Sequence can be either DNA or RNA and submitted as plain text or
    FASTA format.
          </p>
    </div>

    <h3><a href="#">How many siRNAs should I test?</a></h3>
    <div>
      <p>In our hands,
    in the context of miRNA/shRNA expression vectors, designing 4
    sequences typically results in at least one effective sequence. That
    being said, our program does not score or rank potency, so if you
    want to see close to 100% knockdown of your target, either look to
    the literature or other websites for additional potency criteria or
    design more sequences.
          </p>
    </div>

    <h3><a href="#">How many sequences can I input at a time?</a></h3>
    <div>
      <p>
      
    The siRNA design tool is limited to three sequences at a time, up to
    20kb in total. The tool to evaluate siRNA sequences is limited to 10
    siRNAs.
          </p>
    </div>

    <h3><a href="#">What do the lowercase letters mean in the output
      siRNA and passenger strand sequences?</a></h3>
    <div>
      <p> The lowercase letters
    represent G:U wobbles introduced into the siRNA sequence to improve
    loading of the guide strand into the RNAi effector complex, RISC,
    while reducing/eliminating loading of the passenger strand. If the
    passenger strand is loaded, it too can impart off-target effects.
    Northern blots to detect the passenger strand, or reporter
    constructs with artificial binding sites can be used to assess
    passenger strand loading if it is suspected.
          </p>
    </div>

    <h3><a href="#">What does the "NN" at the end of the passenger
      strand mean?</a></h3>
    <div>
      <p> This means that these two bases can vary and
    don't depend on the target sequence. In the context of siRNA design,
    these bases are classically chimeric DNA bases, dTdT. However, if
    these duplexes will be put in the context of a miRNA or shRNA
    shuttle, these nucleotides should match those that are typically at
    this position in the shuttle of choice.
          </p>
    </div>

    <h3><a href="#">What are the "miRNA seed match" and "miRNA
      conservation" columns in the output?</a></h3>
    <div>
      <p> Many microRNAs (miRNAs)
    are highly conserved with conserved target sites in mRNA 3'UTRs.
    Target site conservation tends to the most predictive factor of site
    functionality. These columns show whether the siRNA's seed sequence
    matches the seed sequence of a known miRNA. H(uman), M(ouse) and
    D(og) in the conservation column give a sense of how conserved the
    miRNA is. H, M or D alone means that the miRNA is restricted to a
    particular species or that lineage. H, M on the other hand means
    that orthologus miRNAs are found in both human and mouse. H, M and D
    mean that the microRNA is at least conserved between those species,
    and are often much more conserved than that. The more conserved, the
    more likely they have conserved, functional sites. We suggest
    avoiding siRNAs with miRNA seed sequences, because it is likely that
    the binding sites have a higher probability of being off-targeted
    than our calculations predict.
          </p>
    </div>

    <h3><a href="#">How is POTS calculated?</a></h3>
    <div>
      <p> POTS is calculated
    based on known miRNA targeting rules. Three primary site types are
    commonly described that are more predictive of efficacy than minimal
    6mer match: (in decreasing order of potency)
    8mer&gt;7mer-M8&gt;7mer-1A&gt;&gt;6mer. Using available microarray
    data for siRNA expression studies, we predicted site types for each
    siRNA and calculated the probability that a transcript with a single
    site of any type would be down-regulated at least 1.5 fold. The
    average probabilities for each site type were applied to all
    7mer/target pairs to estimate the number of transcripts that would
    actually be down regulated by the siRNA. The "More Info" link on the
    output page has an option to show the summaries for each site type
    that contributed to the POTS value.
          </p>
    </div>

    <h3><a href="#">My siRNA has a low POTS. Why is it killing my
      cells? / My siRNA has a high POTS, but I haven't noticed any
      problems. Should I be concerned?</a></h3>
    <div>
      <p>POTS cannot determine
    whether a particular siRNA will be toxic or cause "noticeable"
    off-target effects. By choosing sequences with lower POTS, you
    simply decrease the probability of down regulating a large number of
    transcripts and/or decrease the likelihood of hitting an "important"
    transcript(s). If you suspect seed-mediated off-targeting is an
    issue, either design more sequences, or create a seed-match control.
    A seed-match control has the same seed as the siRNA, but has
    mismatches (usually in the middle around bases 10-11) to the
    intended target. This control will not repress the intended target,
    but should maintain a similar off-targeting profile. Alternatively,
    do a rescue experiment to add back a mutated version of your target
    transcript that cannot be regulated by the siRNA. If either results
    in rescue of your toxic/undesired phenotype, your problem is not
    seed-mediated off targeting. If your siRNA with a high POTS score
    does not appear to affect your cells - great! Still, proper controls,
    such as those described above, will ensure that any results you see
    are actually due to knock down of your intended target.
          </p>
    </div>

    <h3><a href="#">I didn't get any sequences with POTS less than 30.
      What should I do?</a></h3>
    <div>
      <p> 30 should not be thought of as a strict
    cutoff. If you need to go higher, test just as you would siRNAs with
    lower POTS. If you include proper controls, find no toxicity and
    your results seem specific to knockdown of your target gene, you can
    feel confident with your results. Alternatively, decrease G/C's
    required at 5' end of passenger or widen slightly G/C% to loosen the
    potency filtering options further. Additional testing will need to
    be done to ensure proper strand loading and efficacy.
  </p>

    <strong> I got back dozens of candidate siRNAs with POTS
      &lt; 30. How can I shrink my list?</strong><br />
  <ol>
    <li>Modify input criteria: You can click the "Update
      parameters" button and modify your input criteria. Maximize G/C's
      required at 5' end of passenger or limit to a lower G/C content.</li>
    <li>Look at the regions targeted by the siRNAs: Pick sequences
      that do not target regions with SNPs or differentially-spliced
      exons. You can also search for siRNAs targeting the 3'UTR to
      facilitate rescue experiments, since you do not have to do
      site-directed mutagenesis.</li>
    <li>Pick the most potent sequences: Look in the literature or
      other siRNA design programs to find additional criteria that tend
      to be more predictive of potent sequences. Alternatively, use our
      "Evaluate siRNA" tool to check POTS for the top siRNAs predicted
      for potency by the other design programs.</li>
  </ol>
         
    </div>

    <h3><a href="#">Are there differences in POTS between species?</a></h3>
    <div>
      <p> 
    The actual POTS will differ slightly between species simply because
    of differences in the number and length of 3'UTR sequences. Based on
    POTS comparison between human and mouse, the rank-order of the seeds
    do not significantly change. In other words, a low POTS in mouse
    tends to be low in human. That being said, previous research has
    shown that siRNA off-targeting is species-specific. This means that
    while the overall POTS is not likely to change drastically, the
    specific transcripts that actually change due to off-targeting will
    likely be different.
  </p>
    </div>

    <h3><a href="#"> Since POTS is calculated based on all 3'UTRs will
      off-targeting potential be different in different cells and
      tissues?</a></h3>
    <div>
      <p> We have calculated tissue-specific POTS based on
    expression data from 177 different human tissues and cell lines,
    using 3'UTR sequences only for the transcripts present in each
    tissue. Because POTS is based on the number of target sites, the
    POTS value differs in each tissue depending on the number of
    expressed transcripts; however, there was no significant change in
    POTS rank order. In other words, the order of siRNAs ranked by POTS
    using all 3'UTR sequences varied little with the order using only
    the 3'UTRs present in a specific tissue. That being said, we
    acknowledge that in an experimental setting the specific
    off-targeted genes, and therefore the off-target effects, will
    likely be different. The provided lists of all off-targets can be
    searched for particular genes of concern.
  </p>
    </div>

    <h3><a href="#"> Can I see a list of potentially off-targeted
      genes?</a></h3>
    <div>
      <p>  Yes. Clicking the "More Info" tab on the output page
    will bring up a menu with several options, one of which is a list of
    off-targets. The genes most likely to be down-regulated are shown
    first. The list can be sorted and searched on the site, or can be
    exported to a CSV file which can be opened in programs like
    Microsoft Excel.
  </p>
    </div>

    <h3><a href="#"> Should I choose to BLAST the 18-mer or 21-mer?</a></h3>
    <div>
      <p> 
    The 18mer represents the "core" sequence that is often used for this
    purpose. Studies have suggested that positions 1, 20 and 21 of the
    antisense strand have little impact on silencing efficacy when
    mismatches to the intended target are introduced. The 18-mer is best
    to use when searching for off-targets, so mismatches to the terminal
    nucleotides are not counted against it. The 21-mer may be better to
    use to find "on-targets" - other transcript isoforms, close paralogs,
    or the same gene in another species.
  </p>
</div>
]]></column>
 </insert>
</changeSet>



<changeSet author="default" id="site_content_3">
 <insert tableName="site_content">
   <column name="label">toolinfo.sirnalookup</column>
   <column name="page">tools.html</column>
   <column name="content"><![CDATA[
 <h2>siRNA POTS Lookup</h2>
    <div class="tabs">
  <ul>
    <li><a href="#summary2">Summary</a></li>
    <li><a href="#input2">Input</a></li>
    <li><a href="#output2">Output</a></li>

  </ul>
  <div id="summary2">
<p>This tool allows researchers to determine the
 off-targeting potential for siRNAs they have 
 already designed. Input can be a list of sequences, 
 separated by a line break, corresponding to the 
 antisense sequence. Output not only provides the POTS for the siRNA, 
but also a percentile score that shows the percent 
of seed sequences with worse POTS values.</p>

  <a class="btn" href="tools/lookup/evaluate.html">Run siRNA POTS Lookup</a>

  </div>
  <div id="input2">
  <p>
  siRNA antisense sequences (limit 20)
  <br/>
NOTE: For multiple sequences, enter one per line.
</p> 

  </div>
  <div id="output2">
  The output provides the following information:
  <br/>
  <br/>
 <div id="lookupHelpAccordion">
      <h3><a href="#">Input Order</a></h3>
      <div>
<p>The order the sequences were entered.
          </p>
    </div>


    

     
  
      <h3><a href="#">POTS (Probability of Off-Targeting Score)</a></h3>
       <div>
       <p>This is
      a representation of the off-targeting potential of a given
      sequence that combines seed complement frequencies as well as
      estimates of their probability of being off-targeted if an
      experiment overexpressing that siRNA. Probabilities are assigned
      by first categorizing seed matches based on rules used by the
      Targetscan algorithm used for predicting targets for endogenous
      miRNAs:
      </p>
      In increasing order of potency:
    
        <ul>
          <li>6mer: Seed match only to nt 2-7</li>
          <li>7mer-1A: In addition to a seed match to nt 2-7, an
            "A" nt is found in the target across from nt1.</li>
          <li>7mer-M8: Seed match extends to nt 2-8.</li>
          <li>8mer: A combination of a 1A and M8 site</li>
        </ul>
    <p>Microarray data were used to estimate the probability that a
      gene containing a seed match of a particular type would be
      down-regulated at least 1.5 fold relative to the control
      conditions. These probabilities are applied to each predicted
      target, and used to calculate an overall score for a particular
      seed sequence.</p>
    <p>See the Targetscan documentation and literature for more
      information.</p>
          </div>

    <h3><a href="#">Percentile (% worse)</a></h3>
    <div>
    <p> The percent of all 7mer
      sequences with a worse (higher) POTS value
   </p>
          </div>



    <h3><a href="#">Seed Sequence</a></h3>
    <div>
    <p>This is the seed sequence for the siRNA
      used for calculating POTS.<br />
</p>
          </div>


    <h3><a href="#">miRNA seed</a></h3>
    <div>
    <p>If the seed of the siRNA matches a
      known endogenous miRNA, the matching miRNA family is presented
      here. We suggest avoiding sequences with miRNA seeds, as many
      predicted miRNA binding sites have evolved to facilitate miRNA
      accessibility. Consequently, work developing miRNA seed targeting
      rules demonstrated a much higher probability of being targeted
      than we have predicted from artificial siRNA expression data.
</p>
          </div>
    <h3><a href="#">miRNA Conservation</a></h3>
    <div>
    <p> This represents the
      conservation of the miRNA with a matching seed sequence. H(uman),
      M(ouse) and D(og) are given as representative species. Sequences
      with only one of the three letters shows that the miRNA is
      specific to that species or evolutionary lineage. H,M says that
      orthologus miRNAs are found in both human and mouse genomes. H,M,D
      means that the miRNA is at the very least conserved in those 3
      species, and are often much more conserved than that. The more
      conserved a miRNA is, the more likely conserved, functional target
      sites exist.
      </p>
   </div>

  </div>
    <script>
  $(function() {
    $( "#lookupHelpAccordion" ).accordion({
      autoHeight: false,
      navigation: true
    });
  });

  </script>
   </div>
</div>
]]></column>
 </insert>
</changeSet>

<changeSet author="default" id="site_content_4">
 <insert tableName="site_content">
   <column name="label">toolinfo.addinfo</column>
   <column name="page">tools.html</column>
   <column name="content"><![CDATA[
 <h2>Additional Features</h2>
   These options are available in <strong>both tools</strong> by clicking the "Off-Target Details" button on the result of interest.
    <br/>
     <br/><p>
 
          <strong>Details of POTS score:</strong><br/> This provides
          summary information on the total number of predicted
          off-targets and the distribution of the various "site-types"
          found in those predicted targets. The POTS value is calculated
          by analyzing the potential off-target genes for seed matches
          conforming to known endogenous microRNA targeting rules.
          "8mer" sites tend to be the most potent followed by (in
          decreasing order) 7mer-M8, 7mer-1A and 6mer.
           <br/>
             <br/>
          <strong>Potential off-target list:</strong><br/> A list of probable off-target genes
          rank-ordered by individual transcript Probability of
          Off-Target Score (tPOTS). tPOTS is calculated based on the
          number and type of seed matches found in that transcript. The
          number of 8mer, 7mer-M8, 7mer-1A and 6mer sites are also
          shown. The entire list of off-targets can be exported to a CSV
          file to analyze as a simple spreadsheet.
          <br/> 
            <br/>
         <strong>Run BLAST search:</strong><br/>
          This is a link to the NCBI nucleotide blast page. In addition
          to seed-mediated off-targets, siRNAs can have more extensive
          binding to mRNAs outside of the 3'UTR. The option to search
          the full 21-mer, or the core 18-mer are provided (p1 and
          p20/21 mismatches often show negligible impact on silencing
          efficacy). Previous studies have suggested avoiding hits with
          0 or 1 mismatches, although 2 and 3 mismatches can still
          mediate silencing. In addition, this feature can be used to
          look for potentially desirable "on-targets". Search for hits
          to known gene paralogs or to see if your sequence would likely
          target the orthologous transcript in another species.
          </p>
]]></column>
 </insert>
</changeSet>


<changeSet author="default" id="site_content_5">
 <insert tableName="site_content">
   <column name="label">toolinfo.sirna</column>
   <column name="page">tools.html</column>
   <column name="content"><![CDATA[
   <h2>siSPOTR - siRNA Design Tool</h2>
<div class="tabs">
  <ul>
    <li><a href="#summary1">Summary</a></li>
       <li><a href="#input1">Input</a></li>
    <li><a href="#output1">Output</a></li>

  </ul>
  <div id="summary1">

	<p>This simple interface allows a 
	user to paste or upload a candidate 
	mRNA sequence (plain or FASTA format) 
	intended for knockdown, and produces 
	an output of candidate siRNAs sorted 
	with the lowest POTS (off-targeting 
	potential) at the top. The output 
	provides the actual sense and 
	antisense sequences to order, 
	making sequence modifications 
	to improve loading of the 
	appropriate strand. 
	</p>
  <br/>
  <div >
  <a class="btn" href="tools/sispotr/design.html">Run siSPOTR - siRNA Design</a>
  </div>
  </div>
  <div id="input1">
  
 <jsp:include page="info/sispotrInputText.jsp"></jsp:include>
  </div>
  <div id="output1">
  The output provides the following information regarding the candidate sequence:
  <br/>
  <br/>
  <div id="helpAccordion">
      <h3><a href="#">Rank</a></h3>
      <div>
<p>Rank position of the siRNA in regards to
      POTS. Lower=less off-target potential.
          </p>
    </div>

    <h3><a href="#">Start Position</a></h3>
    <div>
      <p>Shows the location of the siRNA binding
      site in the input sequence.
      </p>
    </div>
    
       <h3><a href="#">% G/C Content</a></h3>
       <div>
       <p>
       Shows what percent of the siRNA
      sequence is composed of G's and C's. Default criteria set a
      generous range of 20-70%. Potent siRNAs have been found with G/C
      content in this range.
      </p>
      </div>
     
  
      <h3><a href="#">POTS (Probability of Off-Targeting Score)</a></h3>
       <div>
       <p>This is
      a representation of the off-targeting potential of a given
      sequence that combines seed complement frequencies as well as
      estimates of their probability of being off-targeted if an
      experiment overexpressing that siRNA. Probabilities are assigned
      by first categorizing seed matches based on rules used by the
      Targetscan algorithm used for predicting targets for endogenous
      miRNAs:
      </p>
      In increasing order of potency:
    
        <ul>
          <li>6mer: Seed match only to nt 2-7</li>
          <li>7mer-1A: In addition to a seed match to nt 2-7, an
            "A" nt is found in the target across from nt1.</li>
          <li>7mer-M8: Seed match extends to nt 2-8.</li>
          <li>8mer: A combination of a 1A and M8 site</li>
        </ul>
    <p>Microarray data were used to estimate the probability that a
      gene containing a seed match of a particular type would be
      down-regulated at least 1.5 fold relative to the control
      conditions. These probabilities are applied to each predicted
      target, and used to calculate an overall score for a particular
      seed sequence.</p>
    <p>See the Targetscan documentation and literature for more
      information.</p>
          </div>

    <h3><a href="#">Percentile (% worse)</a></h3>
    <div>
    <p> The percent of all 7mer
      sequences with a worse (higher) POTS value
   </p>
          </div>

    <h3><a href="#">Seed Sequence</a></h3>
    <div>
    <p>This is the seed sequence for the
      siRNA used for calculating POTS.
 </p>
          </div>


    <h3><a href="#">miRNA seed</a></h3>
    <div>
    <p>If the seed of the siRNA matches a
      known endogenous miRNA, the matching miRNA family is presented
      here. We suggest avoiding sequences with miRNA seeds, as many
      predicted miRNA binding sites have evolved to facilitate miRNA
      accessibility. Consequently, work developing miRNA seed targeting
      rules demonstrated a much higher probability of being targeted
      than we have predicted from artificial siRNA expression data.
</p>
          </div>
    <h3><a href="#">miRNA Conservation</a></h3>
    <div>
    <p> This represents the
      conservation of the miRNA with a matching seed sequence. H(uman),
      M(ouse) and D(og) are given as representative species. Sequences
      with only one of the three letters shows that the miRNA is
      specific to that species or evolutionary lineage. H,M says that
      orthologus miRNAs are found in both human and mouse genomes. H,M,D
      means that the miRNA is at the very least conserved in those 3
      species, and are often much more conserved than that. The more
      conserved a miRNA is, the more likely conserved, functional target
      sites exist.
      </p>
          </div>

  </div>
    <script>
  $(function() {
    $( "#helpAccordion" ).accordion({
      autoHeight: false,
      navigation: true
    });
  });

  </script>
   </div>

   </div>
]]></column>
 </insert>
</changeSet>


<changeSet author="default" id="site_content_6">
 <insert tableName="site_content">
   <column name="label">designpage.overview</column>
   <column name="page">tools/sispotr/design.html</column>
   <column name="content"><![CDATA[
       <h2>Overview</h2>
    <p>siSPOTR is a RNAi design tool that produces candidate siRNAs and shRNA with the lowest off-targeting potential for a given target transcript. Instructions </p>


    <h3>Input</h3>
<ol>
  <li><strong>Input sequence(s) for siRNA design.</strong> Click
    the appropriate button to paste or upload the sequence(s). Single
    sequences can be in plain or FASTA format. Multiple sequences
    require FASTA formatting.</li>
  <li><strong>Select the number of candidates desired in
      the output.</strong>
  </li>
  <li><strong>(Advanced) Modify input parameters:</strong>
    <ul>
      <li><strong>GC Content (%Min/Max):</strong> Filters candidate
        sequences based on specified GC content range.</li>
      <li><strong>5' Passenger G/C Number:</strong> Forces the
        passenger strand to have high 5' end stability. This decreases
        likelihood of loading the unintended (passenger) strand.
        Additional parameters to promote guide strand loading are
        automatically included in the design.</li>
      <li><strong>Pol III Expression:</strong> Removes sequences
        with &ge;4 T/U's. Stretches of 4 or more U's can serve as a
        termination signal for RNA Pol III. Since many shRNA/artificial
        miRNA expression vectors use Pol III promoters (e.g. U6, H1) to
        drive expression, these sequences should be avoided to prevent
        pre-mature transcript termination.</li>
    </ul></li>
  <li><strong>Run siSPOTR</strong>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Browse additional off-target information
      (Highly Recommended): Click "Off-Target Details" to:</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>BLAST against transcript databases</li>
      <li>View the overall number of off-targets and the
        distribution of more potent seed site-types (7mer-1A, 7mer-M8,
        8mer)</li>
      <li>View/download list of all predicted off-targets with
        site-type information</li>
    </ul></li>
</ol>
]]></column>
 </insert>
</changeSet>

<changeSet author="default" id="site_content_7">
 <insert tableName="site_content">
   <column name="label">resultstable.header</column>
   <column name="page">tools/sispotr/displayResults.html?type=sirna</column>
   <column name="content"><![CDATA[
         <div id="helpcontent" style="float:left;width:55%;padding:10px;">
  <h3>Output</h3>
          <p>The output provides the actual sense and antisense sequences
      to order, making appropriate sequence modifications to improve
      loading of the antisense strand. In addition, the output provides
      the following information regarding the candidate sequence:</p>
      <br/>
  <a href="../../../tools.html" target="_blank">Additional Info</a>
  <br/>
  <br/>
  <a href="../../../help.html" target="_blank">Frequently Asked Questions (click to open in new window)</a>
  </div>
  <div id="helpContainer2" style="float:right;width:40%;padding:10px;">
    <h3>Additional Information (Off-Target Details button)</h3>
    <p>
       These options are available by clicking the "Off-Target Details" button in the first column of the result of interest.
    </p>
  <a href="../../../tools.html" target="_blank">Additional Info</a>
        </div>
', 'resultssirna.help', 'tools/sispotr/displayResults.html?type=sirna');
INSERT INTO site_content VALUES (74, '		  <th>
		  
		  <a class="pop-right" rel="tooltip" data-original-title="Off-Target Details" 
          data-content="BLAST sequence, POTS score details, off-target list" 
          >
Off-Target Details
          <i class="icon-question-sign"></i></a>

		  
		  
          <th>
          
          <a class="pop-right" rel="tooltip" data-original-title="Rank" 
          data-content="Rank position of the siRNA in regards to POTS. Lower=less off-target potential" 
          >
Rank
          <i class="icon-question-sign"></i></a>

          
          
          <th> 
           <a class="pop-right" rel="tooltip" data-original-title="Start Position " 
          data-content="Location of the siRNA binding site in the input sequence" 
        >Start Position
          <i class="icon-question-sign"></i></a>

          
          
          
          <th>
          <a class="pop-right"  rel="tooltip" data-original-title="POTS" 
          data-content="Probability of Off-Targeting Score. Ideal score &lt;=50" 
         >
POTS
          <i class="icon-question-sign"></i></a>

          
         
          <th>
          <a  class="pop-right" rel="tooltip" data-original-title="Percentile (%&nbsp;worse)" 
          data-content="% of all 7mers with a worse POTS value." 
          >
Percentile (%&nbsp;worse)

          <i class="icon-question-sign"></i></a>

          
  
          <th>
           <a  class="pop-right" rel="tooltip" data-original-title="Guide (Antisense)" 
          data-content="Strand that mediates silencing." 
          id="guide_tip">
Guide (Antisense)

          <i class="icon-question-sign"></i></a>

          
          
        
          <th>
          <a   class="pop-right" class="pop-right" rel="tooltip" data-original-title="Passenger (Sense)" 
          data-content="Target sequence. Lowercase indicates G:U wobble creation. 'dTdT' can replace 'NN' when ordering oligos." >

Passenger (Sense)
          <i class="icon-question-sign"></i></a>
  
      
          </th>
          <th>
          <a  class="pop-right" rel="tooltip" data-original-title="Seed Sequence" 
          data-content="Seed sequence for the siRNA used for calculating POTS" >

Seed Sequence
          <i class="icon-question-sign"></i></a>

          
          
          <th>
          <a  class="pop-left" rel="tooltip" data-original-title="miRNA seed" 
          data-content="Shows seed homology to known endogenous microRNAs (miRNA). Recommended to avoid these sequences" 
   >

miRNA seed
          <i class="icon-question-sign"></i></a>

          </th>
          <th>
        
          <a  class="pop-left"  rel="tooltip" data-original-title="miRNA conservation" 
          data-content="Conservation representation of matching miRNA. H(uman), M(ouse) and D(og) are species where miRNA is present. Particularly avoid H,M,D miRNA matches" 
>
miRNA conservation
          <i class="icon-question-sign"></i></a>

          
          </th>
          <th>
          <a   class="pop-left" rel="tooltip" data-original-title="% G/C" 
          data-content="Default (generous) 20-70%. Potent siRNAs have been found that fall this range" >
% G/C
          <i class="icon-question-sign"></i></a>

          </th>

          <th>
          <a   class="pop-left" rel="tooltip" data-original-title="SPS (&Delta;G)" 
          data-content="SPS=Seed Pairing Stability (kcal/mol). 
          More Negative = stronger binding and more potential 
          off-targeting. ">
SPS (&Delta;G)
          <i class="icon-question-sign"></i></a>

          </th>
]]></column>
 </insert>
</changeSet>

</databaseChangeLog>
